<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the supreme authority, the Commons of England assembled in Parliament the humble petition of divers well-affected of the county of Leicester, in behalf of themselves and the nation.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1649</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A94703</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T1741</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason 669.f.14[6]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R211054</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99869790</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99869790</idno>
            <idno type="VID">162994</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A94703)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 162994)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 246:669f14[6])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the supreme authority, the Commons of England assembled in Parliament the humble petition of divers well-affected of the county of Leicester, in behalf of themselves and the nation.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament. House of Commons.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Giles Calvert, at the Black-Spread Eagle at the West-end of Pauls,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648 [i.e. 1649]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Includes the Commons response to the said petition, dated: Die Lunae, 19 Martii, 1648 and signed: Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Leicestershire (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:162994:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>To the Supreme Authority,
THE
COMMONS of ENGLAND
Aſſembled in PARLIAMENT:
The humble Petition of divers well-affected of the County of Leiceſter, in behalf of themſelves and
the Nation,</head>
            <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
            <p>THat with much thankfulneſs we acknowledge your continued faithful pains and endeavors for the Nations Peace and Freedom, eſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially
in your late Votes and Acts ſo much conducing to a good Settlement and Reformation (the end and price of all our blood and
treaſure) To the forwarding and promoting whereof, that ſo great a work may ſtill proſper in your hands, We humbly take leave to offer
theſe following particulars to your ſerious conſideration.</p>
            <p>Firſt, That we may not again be ſurprized by any ſudden Invaſion; and to prevent the breaking forth of new flames amongſt our ſelves, We
humbly beg, That the Militia of the Nation may ſpeedily be ſetled and put into good hands, that a ſufficient ſtrength may be in readineſs in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
County to preſerve it ſelf, and how to be in conjunction with others to defend the whole.</p>
            <p>2. That during the neceſſity of continuing the Army on foot, they may be ſo provided for, for future, that they may be leaſt burthenſome to
the Common-wealth; and that preſent and ſpeedy care may be taken to eaſe the people of that intollerable burthen of Free-Quarter, eſpecially
from thoſe that pay all due taxes; to which purpoſe we earneſtly entreat, That all Lands and publique advantages now in your hands, may be
improved and employed towards the pay of the Army, and what they may fall ſhort, that they may be ſupplyed by an equal tax, each County
knowing their Soldiers they are to pay (which will ſave the trouble and charge of many Collectors, Treaſurers, and Receivers, and that then they
only may be lyable to Free Quarter, who reſiſt or delay payment thereof.</p>
            <p>3. And further, to this purpoſe we humbly offer, That whereas there are many publique offices of advantage worth to divers particular men
thouſands by the year, that till the debts of the Nation be duly ſatisfied, and during this great neceſſity of the Commonwealth, there may be
competent ſalleries appointed for the diſcharge of each of them, and that the reſidue of the Revenue belonging to the ſaid great Offices, may
come into the publique Treaſury.</p>
            <p>4. That this Honorable Houſe would pleaſe to ratifie and eſtabliſh ſuch good and wholſome Laws, as may beſt preſerve our juſt Liberties
and Intereſts (and that according to thoſe Laws God gave his people) they may be ſhort, plain and poſitive, and as well themſelves, as all their
practice and proceeds, may be in our known Engliſh Tongue and Hand, and the diſpenſation thereof may be with the moſt eaſe to the people; that
our Law may become by its Reformation, an advantage and remedy, which for ſo long time by corruption hath been ſo heavy a burthen and op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion
to this Nation.</p>
            <p>5. That that unequal, burthenſom, and contentious way of Tythes may be taken away, and a more equal courſe provided for the maintenance
of the Miniſtery.</p>
            <p>6. That all that have had to do with publique Treaſuries, may ſpeedily, by Commiſſioners to that purpoſe, give up their Accompts in Print,
and for the future, that every Twelve moneths Accompts may be publiquely extant for the due ſatisfaction of the Commonwealth.</p>
            <p>7. That every one may injoy the juſt Freedoms to worſhip God according to his Word, without any Coerſive or Reſtrictive courſes to the
contrary.</p>
            <p>8. That (before it be too late) there may be ſome ſpeedy ſupply and relief ſent to our Brethren of <hi>Ireland,</hi> wherein we are ſo nearly concerned.</p>
            <p>9. That there may be ſome effectual proviſion made for the poor, by the improvement of our In-Land Trades, and ſetting up Manufactures
and Work-Houſes in every County, according to that excellent cuſtom of our Neighbors of <hi>Holland,</hi> and that Fen and Forreſt-Lands may be
improved to the ſame purpoſe.</p>
            <p>Theſe being (as we humbly conceive) ſo eſſential to our juſt Rights and effectual ſettlement, will, we hope, admit of your moſt ſerious
Conſideration and Redreſs.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="Parliamentary_record">
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Die Lunae, 19 Martii, 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>THe Houſe being informed, That there were ſome Gentlemen at the Door, they were called in, and preſented a Petition, which after
the Petitioners were withdrawn, was read; and was intituled, <hi>The humble Petition of many of the well-affected in the County of</hi> Leiceſter,
<hi>in the behalf of themſelves and the Nation:</hi> And thereupon the Petitioners were again called in, and Mr. Speaker returned them this Anſwer.</p>
            <p>Gentlemen, You of the County of <hi>Leiceſter,</hi> the Houſe hath read your Petition, and I ſhall as near as I can declare their ſence; The Houſe doth take notice
of the modeſty and diſcretion of the Petition and Petitioners in the way of delivering of it, and the expreſsions in it; The Houſe doth likewiſe take notice of
ſomething out of the Petition that is concerning your County, whoſe readineſs to the Service of the Publique the last Summer, wherein you did real and acceptable
Service to the Commonwealth, and for theſe, and your good affections always to the Publique, The Houſe hath commanded me to return you hearty thanks, and
I do in their name return you hearty thanks for the particulars in the Petition, ſome of them are of great weight and conſequence, fit for you to preſent, and for
them to take conſideration of; ſome of which as taking off Free-Quarter, and others are already in a way of ſettlement; And the whole Houſe is Zealous to
give you and the Kingdom ſatisfaction therein: For the reſt of the particulars, they doubt not but you will leave it to them, as the urgent and important Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs
of the Kingdom will admit to take the ſame into conſideration, and doubt not but to do it ſo, as the Kingdom may receive ſatisfaction and ſafety.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Hen: Scobell, Cleric' Parliament'.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for GILES CALVERT, at the Black-Spread Eagle at the Weſt-end of PAULS, 1648.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
